# 大家好
Hi everyone!
# 今天天氣比較好哦
The weather today is quite good.
# 我來看一下兄弟家的 那麼野池塘啊
I'm coming to take a look at my buddy's, I mean his wild pond.
# 好久都沒來過啦
It has been a long time since my last visit.
# 有點想念
I miss it.
# 可以 可以過去
It's alright. I can walk from here.
# 好多水哇
There's so much water.
# 水都這麼滿
It almost overflows.
# 肯定有魚
There must be fish.
# 你看這裡
Have a look at here!
# 好多蝌蚪哇
There are so many tadpoles.
# 在游來游去
They're swimming around.
# 也有小魚
There are also small fish.
# 大魚沒看到
But I can't see any big fish.
# 你看 這水好多啦 現在
Look! Now there's so much water.
# 放水都不好放 太多水了啦
There's so much water that draining out the water may not be a good idea.
# 下次我用 魚釣來勾
Next time I'll come with a hook, to catch the fish.
# 勾不到的時候就 沒辦法了就放水
Draining out the water is the last resort, when the hook doesn't work.
# 用抽水機來抽
I can use my water pump.
# 我剛才看到好多
I've just seen a lot,
# 好多魚
a lot of fish.
# 看到我都跑
But they ran way when they saw me.
# 小的
This one is small.
# 沒有紅鯉魚
I can't see any red carps.
# 沒紅鯉魚
There are no red carps.
# 你看這個有一棵批把樹哦
Look! Here's a loquat tree.
# 我把它拔出來
Let me pull it out.
# 這里面是兄弟家的菜園
Inside the fence is my buddy's veggie garden.
# 這個兄弟 兄弟種的
This tree was planted, planted by my buddy.
# 它的脖子往外歪 歪出來啦
Its neck is bending out, out of the fence.
# 我把它拔掉
Let me pull it out.
# 拔到那個
I pull it out and then,
# 拔到我們下面那邊去種
and then plant it at our site.
# 還有 這邊還有
There are some more, some more over there.
# 你看 這裡也有一棵
Look! Here's another one.
# 種就種多一點 看下還有沒有
It's better to plant more. Let's see if there are any more.
# 你看 這棵批把樹是野生的哦
Look! This is a wild loquat tree.
# 它就這樣長在河邊
It's simply growing on the riverside.
# 還有的時候就一直
When I was a kid, it was like...
# 現在那麼大啦
But it's that big now.
# 我記得我還小的時候就那麼大一點
I remember that it was just around that big when I was a kid.
# 經常爬上去 現在那麼大啦 這棵樹
I used to climb this tree pretty often. It's so big now.
# 看一下還有沒有
Let me see if there are any more.
# 誒 這里有
Eh? Here's one!
# 這是它的秧
This is its seedling.
# 這裡也有一棵
Here's one more.
And here's one more.
# 這裡也有一棵
# 可以 你看 這有六七棵這個 批把曲
Alright! Look! Here are half a dozen of, you know, loquat seedlings.
# 我們拿到下面去種
Let's plant them down there.
# 兄弟家問口又找到兩棵
I see two more in front of my buddy's door.
# 他家的比較
His seedling are,
# 比較大一點
are a bit larger.
# 這裡有一棵
Here's one.
# 你看 這個很大 好靚
Look! This one is really big, and beautiful!
# 你看 拔了一棵大的
Look! I've picked a big one!
# 大的種到這裡來
I plant the big one here.
# 這樣種下去就可以啦
I only need to leave it here.
# 馬上就要下雨啦
It will be raining very soon.
# 水都不用澆
So I don't even need to water it.
# 等下
It'll,
# 快下點雨就可以啦
it'll be fine as long as there's rain.
# 種了棵
So I'm done with one.
# 還有幾棵 我到那邊去種
There is still a couple more. Let me plant them over there.
# 這個就種到這裡啦
I'll plant this one here.
# 好 這裡種了一棵
Alright! One is planted here!
# 現在全部種好啦
All have been planted now.
# 到時候 到時候我們就有批把吃啦
We'll, we'll have loquats later.
# 今天的視頻到這裡啦
The video ends here.